Witness the beginning of evil.
Resident Evil: Welcome to Raccoon City is a action, horror,
science fiction film directed by Johannes Roberts.
Once the booming home of pharmaceutical giant Umbrella
Corporation, Raccoon City is now a dying Midwestern town.
The company’s exodus left the city a wasteland…with
great evil brewing below the surface.
When that evil is unleashed, the townspeople are forever…changed…and a small group of survivors must
work together to uncover the truth behind Umbrella and make it through the night.
Claire Redfield, played by Kaya Scodelario.
Jill Valentine, played by Hannah John-Kamen.
Chris Redfield, played by Robbie Amell.
Albert Wesker, played by Tom Hopper.
Leon Kennedy, played by Avan Jogia.
Chief Irons, played by Donal Logue.
Resident Evil: Welcome to Raccoon City is a 2021 action horror film based on the Resident Evil video game series by
Capcom, and serves as a reboot and the seventh live-action film of the Resident Evil film series.
Written and directed by Johannes Roberts, the film stars Kaya Scodelario, Hannah
John-Kamen, Robbie Amell, Tom Hopper, Avan Jogia, Donal Logue, and Neal McDonough.
Set in 1998, and primarily adapting the first and second games, it follows a
group of survivors during a zombie outbreak in Raccoon City.
It is the first live-action film in the series not to feature Milla
Jovovich in the lead role of her character Alice.
Development took place in early 2017, after Resident Evil: The Final Chapter was
released, with producer James Wan expressing interest in the project.
Later, Constantin Film chairman Martin Moszkowicz said that a
reboot of the film series was in development.
In the same month, Wan was called to produce the reboot with a script by Greg Russo; subsequently,
Roberts was hired as both writer and director and both Wan and Russo left the project.
Filming began on October 17, 2020, in Greater Sudbury, Ontario, Canada.
The film underwent reshoots in May 2021.
Resident Evil: Welcome to Raccoon City had its world premiere at the Grand Rex in Paris on November 19, 2021, and
was theatrically released on November 24, 2021, in the United States by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film grossed $42 million worldwide and received mixed reviews from critics, who
praised its faithfulness to the first two games, but criticized its writing.
A sequel was planned but cancelled due to the film's commercial failure.
Another reboot is slated to be released on September 18, 2026.
The film explores themes of biological weapon,
orphanage, dystopia, mutant, infection.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.